<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>complete-story &#8211; The Posters Project</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/complete-story/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 17:42:26 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>No metro at Exarchia!</title>
		<link>/no-metro-at-exarchia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[zaaron345]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 17:34:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Greece]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Poster]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social movement]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[complete-story]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[recreated]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=39</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A fight to preserve the historic symbol for civil disobedience in Athens.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" width="595" height="842" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/athens-subway-1x.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-40" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/athens-subway-1x.jpg 595w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/04/athens-subway-1x-212x300.jpg 212w" sizes="(max-width: 595px) 100vw, 595px" /></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-table is-style-stripes"><table><tbody><tr><td><strong>Location</strong></td><td>Athens, Greece</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Media</strong></td><td>Poster</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Type</strong></td><td>Social movements</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Year</strong> <strong>accessed</strong></td><td>2023</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Status</strong></td><td>Recreated</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<p><strong>Translation from Greek:</strong><br>EXARCHIA 2023 RACE<br>for the Neighborhood and the Movement<br>NO METRO IN EXARCHIA SQUARE <br>NO DESTRUCTION OF STREFI HILL<br>NO EVICTION &#8211; NO TOURISTIFICATION</p>



<p></p>



<p>Exarcheia, a neighborhood in central Athens, is famous for its left-wing ideologies. From the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Athens_Polytechnic_uprising">Athens Polytechnic uprising</a> in 1973 (when Greek military killed 40 civilians) to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2008_Greek_riots">2008 Greek riots</a> (which started in Exarcheia), the neighborhood&#8217;s &#8220;anti-authoritarian culture has earned it a reputation for being a state within a state.&#8221; The Athens Polytechnic uprising resulted in the passing of the Academic Asylum Law, which designates university campuses as no-go zone for police and military. The law further contributed to the prevalence of protests within the neighborhood, and the university served as a site of insurgent coordination and a safe haven from police violence. The law would be <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2019/aug/08/greece-scraps-law-banning-police-from-university-campuses">scrapped by the government in 2019</a>.</p>



<p>In 4:30AM of August 2022, <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2022/aug/17/residents-of-athens-lawless-exarchia-square-resist-metro-station-plan">heavily armed units guarded outside the hastily erected metal barricades</a>. Overnight, the once-vibrant Exarcheia square was turned into a no-go zone. The contruction of the metro station started.</p>



<p>Protester said that the public work is in fact a political move. The central-right government has long wanted to <em>cleanup</em> the district. The metro station, together with its destruction of the historical symbol of civil resistance, serves to bury the history of uprising in the face of the government. </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="1024" height="616" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/3468-1024x616.webp" alt="" class="wp-image-41" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/3468-1024x616.webp 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/04/3468-300x180.webp 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/04/3468-768x462.webp 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/04/3468.webp 1240w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption"><em>Protesters hold a banner reading ‘Exarchia has history. Out with the metro’. From <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2022/aug/17/residents-of-athens-lawless-exarchia-square-resist-metro-station-plan">the Guardian</a>.</em></figcaption></figure>



<p></p>



<p>Here is the excerpt of the resolution of the movement, translated from Greek:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p><em>Residents, employees, students, visitors of Exarchia address this resolution to the Minister of Infrastructure &amp; Transport of Greece, Mr. Costas Ah.&nbsp;Karamanlis.</em></p>



<p><em>It was a warm night, before dawn in the center of Athens.&nbsp;The town was quiet and the residents were away on vacation.&nbsp;The shops were closed.&nbsp;At 4:30 am the Greek State launched an unprecedented attack on one of the emblematic places of Athens, Exarchia square.&nbsp;Hundreds of police flooded the streets around the square to enforce the construction of an unwanted metro station and quell public protests against it.&nbsp;They have remained there ever since.&nbsp;So did the people of Exarchia.</em></p>



<p><em>On the day of the operation, despite the prospect of a police crackdown, more than a thousand people, residents of the neighborhood and people of the city gathered in the otherwise quiet, summer streets of Athens to protest and show their solidarity with Exarchia.&nbsp;Hundreds attend the open assembly.&nbsp;Local businesses have filed injunctions against the (public) construction company.&nbsp;Dozens meet daily at 6 a.m. in front of heavily armed police forces, and hundreds take part in the afternoon protests.&nbsp;Intellectuals, academics and artists of authoritarian government practices.&nbsp;have come out en masse against the project.</em></p>



<p><em>Exarcheion Square is a breathing space for workers, visitors, residents, children, and a small square that breaks the concrete monotony of the center of Athens.&nbsp;It is a space of radical ideas, students. It is the home of revolutionary youth, trios, artists and intellectuals.&nbsp;It is the space that marginilizes no newcomers. There has not been a young person in Athens who has not socialized, flirted or casually chatted over a beer or coffee with his/her peers, a visitor who has not attended cultural activities or who did not find shelter from the hot Athenian sun under the shade of the trees of the square.</em></p>



<p><em>Exarchia Square is an international symbol of resistance and political ferment.&nbsp;It is characterized by class solidarity, self-organization, without racial discrimination, coexistence and respect for the diversity of people, guided by the dream of a world of equality and justice.&nbsp;Throughout time, it has been a symbol for LGBTQI+ struggles and a safe space for all oppressed, persecuted or marginalized personalities.</em></p>



<p><em>RIGHT NOW ALL OF THESE ARE THREATENED WITH EXTINCTION by the government&#8217;s insistence on going ahead with a socially rejected project and using our square, the square of all people, as a trophy and landmark in its exclusive agenda.</em></p>
<cite>The Press Project</cite></blockquote>



<p>You can <a href="https://thepressproject.gr/ochi-metro-stin-pl-exarcheion-psifisma-kai-syllogi-ypografon-gia-na-stamatisei-i-kataskevi-stathmou-metro-stin-plateia/">read the full resolution here</a> (in Greek). Background information is from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Exarcheia#Athens_Polytechnic_uprising">Wikipedia</a> and <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2022/aug/17/residents-of-athens-lawless-exarchia-square-resist-metro-station-plan">Guardian</a>. </p>



<p><strong>Recreated</strong>: This poster was recreated in Illustrator, Photoshop and Sketch.</p>



<p></p>



<figure class="wp-block-table is-style-stripes"><table><tbody><tr><td><strong>Download</strong><br>JPG file (full-size): <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1AePVOg1vkux7rrL5OWHGAV5wogPQFrJz/view?usp=sharing" target="_blank">Google Drive</a></td></tr></tbody></table></figure>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
